

Ahmed Hyder Mohammed Alatta

Knowledgeable banker and enthusiastic professional with an MBA degree and more than seven years of experience in banking sector and customer service. I possess a provenability of team work and effectiveorganizational and interpersonal skills with a strong basis of business solutions. I'm currently seeking for a challenging career with reputable bank or large firm on which will make best use of my existing skills and knowledge while also furthering my development.

moodyhyder114@gmail.com Emirates- Dubai Jul 4, 1990 Sudanese

+971582509296 🗆 +971509632980

Experience

Apr 2021-till now, Sudan, Khartoum

ASSISTANT TREASURY MANAGER

ARAB SUDANESE BANK

- Prepares daily pricing list & Managing FCY position.
- · Liaise with designated staff about financial matters.
- · Raises and manage funds for the organization.
- Presents regular reports on the organizations financial position.
- · Manages bank correspondents accounts.
- · Develops and implements cash management operational strategies.
- Prepares needed reports either CBOS reports or internal reports.
- · Provides detailed consolidated cash flow.
- Assists in the development of banking relations.

May 2019- Feb 2021, Sudan, Khartoum

SENIOR TREASURY OFFICER

ALJAZEERA SUDANESE JORDANIAN BANK

- Prepares daily pricing list. Managing FCY position and Make FX deals with customers and correspondents banks.
- Directs daily money market activities (liquidity management).
- Prepares, monitors, and executes lending and borrowing strategies (with Localbanks).
- Prepares and executes investment strategies in capital market Instruments, Manages the Investment in certificates and securities.
- · Prepares daily, weekly and monthly reports.
- Manages shares with the interbank liquidity management fund to achieve the highest return for the bank and working to reduce exchange rate risks.
- Manages and sustaining good relations with correspondents Banks and extends bridges of communication with local banks.

Apr 2018- May 2019, Sudan, Khartoum

Treasury officer

Animal Resources Bank

- I am responsible for the bank's liquidity, ensure that a bank has enough cash available at all times to meet the needs of its primary business operations.
- · Cash forecasting.
- plan for investment purposes.
- individual investment Management & Bank Relation one of my main duties.
- Maintaining excellent relations with the investment community for fund raising purposes.

Apr 2015- Aug 2017, Sudan, Khartoum

Customer service representative:

Sudanese Egyptian bank

Respond to customers enquires, requests, complaints over phone and in person as front desk.

Using customer handling, deep thinking, multitasking and problem-solving techniques to provide excellent service that satisfy customers.

All that with compliance with the bank policies and requirements.

Mar 2014- Mar 2015, Sudan, Khartoum

Universal teller:

Sudanese Egyptian bank

- Assist customers with processing transactions, such as deposits, withdrawals, or payments, resolving complaints.
- Handling currency, transactions, and confidential information in a responsible manner by system.
- Maintain and balance cash drawers and reconciling discrepancies.

Education

2007 - 2011, Sudan, Khartoum

 BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ECONOMICS AND POLITICAL SCIENCES,

UNIVERSITY OF KHARTOUM

2017 - 2018, Sudan, Khartoum

MBA

SUDAN INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Skills

Languages

Teamwork

• Problem-Solving

Arabic: Native
English: Fluent

- · Customer service
- Multitasking
- Listening
- · Deep thinking
- · Microsoft office

Certifications & Courses

May 2015

HUMAN PROFESSIONAL BUILDING, INSANE CENTER

OCTOBER 2012

ICDL, UNIVERSITY OF KHARTOUM